Guide to the Oregon State University Military Photographs Collection 1875-1975
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Inter War Years, 1919-1939; Series III
  - OAC Military Tournament/Inspection Day - Pre 1925, circa 1920
    - Officers with man and woman inspection day, circa 1920; P002:690; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      This photograph is poorly focused, and the man in civilian clothes might be one of the military department observers. Officers are wearing dress uniforms for inspection day.
    - Cadets resting in field, rifles stacked, inspection day, circa 1920; P002:691; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadets are resting in high grass field. Rifles are stacked at side of group.
    - Spectator crowd on field with cadets, inspection day, circa 1920; P002:692; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Spectators watching the inspection day formations of OAC Cadets
    - OAC ROTC Officers meeting with unidentified man, circa 1920; P002:693; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Photo includes the US Army officers assigned to OAC ROTC Program meeting with an unidentified man in suit. Possibly Military Department representative here to review cadet regiment.
    - Officer bending down to view baby carriage, mother looks on, circa 1920; P002:694; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      The high collar tunic was still in issue up to 1925, which places the uniform styles in the circa 1920 period. Photograph shows military officer bending down to view baby in carriage while the mother looks on. Cadet officer observes, holding megaphone in white gloved hands.
    - Cadet color guard marching on parade field, circa 1920; P002:696; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet color guard marching across parade field in front of large crowd of spectators.
  - OSC Military Tournament/Inspection Day - 1925 to 1939, circa 1927
    This sub series contains photos of Inspection Day formations of OAC Cadets wearing later type 1925 style uniforms. Dating of sub series based on collar design of officers jackets. Many of the photos appear to be of Inspection Day Formations, all are related.
    - Inspection Day formation OAC Cadet Regiment, circa 1927; P002:535; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide angle view of cadet formations on lower campus, possibly mid 1920s. Cadets are formed into companies with officers on right. Detail of photo indicates service caps and high leather boots.
    - Trick photography way before Photoshop, OAC Cadet Band, circa 1927; P002:536; 2.0 3 x 5 prints; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide angle photo of OAC Cadet band in formation on parade field, probably Inspection Day in mid 1920s. Company formation of cadets on right with officers in field. Band in marching formation with instruments. Double exposure trick photography changing perspective. Band in foreground is smaller than the band in the background.
    - Inspection Day formation, duplicate of P002:535, circa 1927; P002:537; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide angle view of cadet formations on lower campus, possibly mid 1920s. Cadets are formed into companies with officers on right. Detail of photo indicates service caps and high leather boots, uniforms could date to circa 1925. Duplicate print of P002:535
    - Inspection Day Company formations, wide view, circa 1927; P002:538; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide angle view of cadet formations on lower campus, possibly mid 1920s. Cadets are formed into companies with officers on right. Detail of photo indicates service caps and high leather boots, uniforms could date to circa 1925. Photo is related to P002:535
    - Commanding Officer inspecting color guard, circa 1927; P002:539; 3.0 3 x 5 prints; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      US Army officer inspecting OAC Cadet Color Guard, probably inspection day. Detail of photo indicates service caps and high leather boots, uniforms of officers include collar design post 1925.
    - Inspection Day cadets moving into formation, circa 1927; P002:540; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Cadet companies moving into formation on parade field. Inspection day, mid 1920s. Monroe street churches on left in background. Detail of photo indicates service caps and high leather boots, uniforms date to circa 1925 or later.
    - Negative, Inspection Day color guard, at attention, circa 1927; P002:541; 3.5X5.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Wide angle view of cadet formations on lower campus, possibly mid 1920s. Color guard formation at attention with officer saluting with sabre. Cadet company formations in background. Detail of photo indicates service caps and high leather boots, uniforms date to post circa 1925.
    - Cadets resting in shade, Inspection Day, circa 1925; P002:792; 3X9 photographic print (Box 1)
      Print of larger panorama. Cadets resting in shade on campus. Notation on reverse states: "Annual Military Inspection Parade - ROTC" Also noted: "1925 Beaver p.174" and "Rec'd May 26 '64 Shriber". Cadets are wearing garrison caps and have web gear with canteens and pouches visible. High collar tunics are consistent with dating.
    - Annual Military Inspection Parade - ROTC, circa 1925; P002:793; 2.5X9.5 photographic print (Box 1)
      Print of larger panoramic photograph. Formations of cadets on parade field, with spectators circa 1925. Photo is marked on reverse "Annual Military Inspection parade - ROTC" Also marked in lower right corner: "1925 Beaver p.174, Rec'd May 26 '64 Shriber". Wide angle shot of cadets on field. Spectators on right looking on.
    - Armory at night time with automobiles, circa 1925; P002:794; 4X9 photographic print (Box 1)
      Print of larger panoramic photo. Night time photograph of the Armory (Mc Alexander Field House) with period automobiles. Sign over door of building "Military Tournament - April 27th" Markings in pencil on reverse: "The cadet corps at the time of the annual Military inspection has succeeded in winning the Distinguished Star rating during the past five seasons, the entire equipment of all units of ROTC is used for the parade. 1925 Beaver p.174" The photo is also marked in lower right with "Rec'd May 26 '64 Shriber".
  - Interwar Years - Negatives, 1919-1939
    Collection of 4x5 negatives, various subjects during the interwar years. Many of the negatives correspond with prints in this series. Some of the negatives are related to the prints as different views, same subjects. Arranged numerically within the sub series folder.
    - Army ROTC Drill Team with M1903 Springfield Rifles, circa 1939; P002:044; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      10 Army Drill Team members with Officer. Rifles are 1903 Springfield bolt action. Men are wearing garrison caps in dress uniforms. Officer wearing dress tunic with Sam Browne belt and brimmed cap.
    - Officers and escorts procession at Military Ball, circa 1937; P002:53; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      The annual military ball at Oregon State was the high point of the cadet year. The elaborate backdrop with anti-aircraft guns and bombs for the band was probably erected in the Memorial Union ballroom. Officers and their escorts are being greeted by the Commandant. Circa dating of 1937 is indicated by uniforms. This photo was probably used for OSC publication.
    - Governor Charles Martin presenting ribbon to Cadet honor guard, circa 1938; P002:059; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Governor Charles Martin presenting award ribbon to cadet honor guard on their company pennant. Previous description (Unconfirmed) dates the event to 1938. Military uniforms conform to this circa date. Parade grounds adjacent to Weatherford hall.
    - ROTC officers in dress uniform graduation diplomas in hands, circa 1935; P002:060; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      4 cadet officers in dress uniform with diplomas in hands. Reviewing officer on left in full dress uniform. Parade grounds formation back ground. Uniforms date to 1935 or earlier. High boots with ceremonial spurs and riding pants (Jodhpurs) indicate cavalry officers. The Sam Browne belts worn with dress uniform were issued up to 1940. Cadets appear to be holding certificates or diplomas. Possible use in the Beaver Yearbook or the Oregon Stater magazine.
    - Five cadet officers in dress uniforms circa 1938, P002:061; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Five cadet officers in dress uniforms. Date of negative based on 1938 written on edge of negative. Photograph of cadet officers is similar to Beaver Yearbook listing of this period. Uniforms are correct for circa dating.
    - ROTC Cadets in formation for review on parade field, circa 1939; P002:063; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Stock photograph of formations of cadets on parade grounds. Prior description lists photograph circa 1939. Similar image is included in 1938 Beaver yearbook. Negative is probably from series of photos used.
    - Cadet formation in front of Armory circa 1939, P002:066; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Formation of cadets in front of McAlexander Field House Armory. Dating of photo to 1939 is possible, based on uniforms. Possible use of the negatives for the Beaver Yearbook or the Oregon Stater magazine.
    - Drum Major cadets in dress uniform circa 1935, P002:067; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Two drum major cadets in dress uniform on parade field. Prior description identifies men as Martin Coopy and Tom Stevenson. Uniforms indicate probable dating of 1935.
    - Cadet companies on parade field, inspection day, circa 1937; P002:452; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Overhead view (possibly from Weatherford Hall tower?) of parade field with reviewing stand. Cadet companies are marching past in review. OSC Cadet band playing in background.
    - Reviewing stand dignitaries on inspection day, circa 1937; P002:453; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Reviewing stand for cadet inspection day by Oregon Governor Martin. Various photos in this series show this stand, probably on parade field adjacent to Weatherford Hall. Cadet officer is saluting dignitaries with his sabre.
    - Reviewing stand dignitaries, Inspection Day, circa 1937; P002:454; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Reviewing stand for cadet inspection day by Oregon Governor Martin (?). Various photos in this series show this stand, probably on parade field adjacent to Weatherford Hall. President Peavy appears to be seated in group.
    - Group of dignitaries lined up for presentations, inspection day, circa 1937; P002:455; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Reviewing stand for cadet inspection day by Oregon Governor Martin. Various photos in this series show this stand, probably on parade field adjacent to Weatherford Hall. Dignitaries are lined up for presentations (Commissions ?) circa 1937.
    - Cadet companies on parade in front of reviewing stand, inspection day, circa 1937; P002:456; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Overhead view (possibly from Weatherford Hall tower?) of parade field with reviewing stand. Cadet companies are marching past in review. OSC Cadet band playing in background. Circa 1937
    - Cadet formations on parade field, inspection day, circa 1937; P002:457; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Cadet company in formation for review, inspection day. Of note is photographer with camera on left.
    - Officers and dignitaries review cadets on inspection day, circa 1937; P002:460; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade field. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin (?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs. Circa dating of 1937 is based on uniforms and President Peavy's attendance.
    - ROTC Artillery pass in review, circa 1937; P002:462; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Line of ROTC Artillery Unit guns pass in review on inspection day. Cadet formations in background of parade field. The artillery pieces appear to be 37mm light field artillery.
    - Cadet formations on parade field, Weatherford Hall in background, circa 1937; P002:463; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade field. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin (?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs. Good view of Weatherford Hall in background.
    - Dignitaries reviewing cadet formations, circa 1937; P002:464; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade field. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin(?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs.
    - Officers and dignitaries review artillery parade, circa 1937; P002:466; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of OSC Artillery Unit on parade. ROTC Military Inspection Day, Governor Martin(?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs.
    - Officers and Dignitaries review cadet formations, circa 1937; P002:467; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade filed. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin(?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs.
    - Governor Martin reviewing line of cadet officers, circa 1937; P002:468; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade filed. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin (?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs.
    - Dignitaries salute as colors pass in review, circa 1937; P002:469; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade filed. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin (?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs. Line of dignitaries and officers salute the colors as they pass in review.
    - Dignitaries and Officers saluting passing colors, circa 1937; P002:470; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
    - Cadet corps in formation, Armory in background, circa 1937; P002:471; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Entire cadet corps in formation in front of Armory, probably listening to speaker. Photo appears to belong to same group from inspection day with governor Martin in attendance.
    - Cadet formations pass in review, inspection day, circa 1937; P002:473; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade filed. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin (?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs. Line of dignitaries and officers observe cadet company marching by in formation.
    - Inspection day, Gov. Martin and Pres. Peavy, circa 1937; P002:514; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military officers and civilian dignitaries stand in review of cadet formations on parade field. Probably inspection day, Governor Martin (?) and President Peavy are seen in this group of photographs. Circa dating of 1937 is based on uniforms and President Peavy's attendance. Photographs of "Governor's Inspection Day" appear in the 1938 and 1940 Beaver Yearbooks, photos from this group being used.
    - Cadet formations reviewed by Gov. Martin, circa 1937; P002:515; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
    - Officers and Dignitaries saluting passing colors, circa 1937; P002:516; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
    - groups of cadets by Armory, circa 1937; P002:517; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Groups of cadets in field in front of Armory (now McAlexander Field House). Formations appear to be moving, possibly forming up for inspection day.
    - Artillery pieces on review, circa 1937; P002:518; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Line of ROTC Artillery Unit guns pass in review on inspection day. Cadet formations in background of parade field. The artillery pieces appear to be 37mm light field artillery. This view is similar to P002:462.
    - Dignitaries reviewing cadet formations, circa 1937; P002:520; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Inspection day, cadet company formations being reviewed by dignitaries. Possibly Gov. Martin and President Peavy as seen in other photos in this grouping. Campus buildings in background, parade field adjacent to Men's Dorm (now Weatherford Hall). Photos in this grouping appear in the 1937 and 1940 Beaver yearbooks.
    - OSC ROTC motorized corps passing in review, circa 1937; P002:521; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Inspection day, OSC motorized companies being reviewed by dignitaries. Possibly Gov. Martin and President Peavy as seen in other photos in this grouping. Vintage of vehicles used to date photo to
    - OSC Cadet company at attention being reviewed by Gov. Martin, circa 1937; P002:522; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Inspection day, cadet company formations being reviewed by dignitaries. Possibly Gov. Martin and President Peavy as seen in other photos in this grouping. Campus buildings in background, parade field adjacent to Education building on lower campus. Photos in this grouping appear in the 1937 and 1940 Beaver yearbooks.
    - Cadet officers in formation on inspection day, circa 1937; P002:524; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Inspection day,cadet company formations being reviewed by dignitaries. Possibly Gov. Martin and President Peavy as seen in other photos in this grouping. Uniforms include leather puttees, probably a cavalry unit.
    - Cadet company in front of Armory, circa 1937; P002:526; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Formation of cadets in front of McAlexander Field House Armory. This image is related to P002:066, same pose and location of photo. Possible use of the negatives in the Beaver Yearbook or the Oregon Stater magazine.
    - Artillery being loaded by cadets, action shot, circa 1937; P002:527; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Unit of ROTC Artillery cadets loading their field gun. Action shot showing shell being loaded. Uniforms and equipment can be dated to late 1930s. The photograph is seen in the 1940 Beaver Yearbook in a montage of military subjects.
    - Artillery display, reviewed by officers, circa 1937; P002:528; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Unit of ROTC Artillery cadets loading their field gun. Two officers observe the cadets and their gun. Uniforms and equipment can be dated to late 1930s. The photograph is seen in the 1940 Beaver Yearbook in a montage of military subjects.
    - Artillery display, muzzle view, circa 1937; P002:530; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Unit of ROTC Artillery cadets loading their field gun. View from the muzzle end of the gun. Officer inspecting performance at right. Uniforms and equipment can be dated to late 1930s. The photograph is seen in the 1940 Beaver Yearbook in a montage of military subjects.
    - ROTC encampment on campus, with artillery, circa 1934; P002:532; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Military encampment on campus adjacent to Weatherford Hall circa 1936. Period vehicles including trucks and sedans. Tents of different configurations from 2 man "pup tents" to larger personnel tents. Photographs similar to this grouping are published in Beaver Yearbook, 1936.
    - ROTC encampment on campus, trucks and artillery in view, circa 1934; P002:533; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
    - ROTC encampment on campus, Weatherford Hall parade field, circa 1934; P002:534; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
    - Formation of cadet officers on inspection day, circa 1937; P002:541; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Company of cadet officers at attention with colors on inspection day. The uniforms indicated mid to late 1930s, including leather puttees and jodhpurs riding trousers.
    - Cadet company marching on lower campus with rifles, circa 1937; P002:544; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      OAC Company F marching on lower campus with rifles. Probably inspection day. Men are wearing Garrison caps with class A tunics. Dating to mid 1930s based on uniforms, the OAC on the guidon is probably left over past the change to OSC.
    - ROTC Band drum major in dress uniform, circa 1935; P002:545; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      ROTC Drum major in dress uniform on parade field. Uniforms indicate probable dating of 1935. Possible use of the negatives for the Beaver Yearbook or the Oregon Stater magazine.
    - two ROTC Drum Majors in dress uniforms, circa 1935; P002:546; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Two drum major cadets in dress uniform on parade field. Prior description identifies men as Martin Coopy and Tom Stevenson. Uniforms indicate probable dating of 1935. Images are found in the Beaver Yearbook or the Oregon Stater magazine.
    - ROTC Drum major in dress uniform, circa 1935; P002:547; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      ROTC Drum Major, similar to P002:545, slightly more centered shot. Uniforms indicate probable dating of 1935.
    - Ravages of Venereal Disease cartoon, circa 1930; P002:563; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
      Copy of the famous US Army cartoon about soldiers and VD. "Two girls I know want to meet you in the worst way." C.D. Batchelor, American Social Hygiene Association, circa 1940. This cartoon was done as a series for the military prior to WWII.
  - OSC Rifle Team in Dress Uniforms, circa 1940; P002:028; 4X5 negative (Box 1)
    US Army Cadet rifle team and officer/NCO advisor. Photograph is Pre WWII, uniforms reflect tall boots and Sam Browne belts. Decorations and medals on US Army personnel in back row show service in WWI and top level marksman badges. There is no indication location of the photo. Based on uniforms, photo can be dated from approximately 1925-1940.
  - Group of seated dignitaries with mixed military officers, circa 1940; P002:033; 2.5x3 photographic print (Box 1)
    stamped on reverse "Oregon State College Library Picture Collection" with no data included. Seated dignitaries not identified. Military uniforms date to Pre WWII vintage, cavalry officer 2nd from right wearing high leather boots with ceremonial spurs. Officers uniforms include the Sam Browne belt.
  - Unidentified US Army Captain, informal pose, circa 1940; P002:034; 2.5x3 photographic print (Box 1)
    US Army Captain in dress uniform informal pose. Rack of books in background has copies of the Beaver Yearbook. Military dress uniform dates to pre-WWII vintage, including Sam Browne belt.
  - ROTC Cadet Dress Uniform with Sabre, circa 1926; P002:036 (Box 1)
    Excellent study of Cadet uniform of the late 1920s. Sam Browne belt with cadet's sword, jodhpurs trousers and early style rolled collar (Lapel type) dress blouse. Emblem on left sleeve unique to OAC. Leather leggings or puttees are indicative of calvary as is the lapel badges. Identification of cadet is not given.
  - ROTC Rifle Team in Sweaters with Army advisor, circa 1930; P002:039; 8X10 photographic print (Box 1)
    Oregon State College ROTC Rifle Team, wearing sweaters with logo, holding bolt action 1903 Springfield rifles. Officer and NCO in back row are in dress uniform with leather Sam Browne belts and lapel type jackets. Members of rifle team are not identified.
  - Unidentified Officer dress uniform Pre WWII, circa 1930; P002:041; 3X4 photographic print (Box 1)
    Unidentified officer in dress uniform. Officer is wearing Sam Browne belt with one overseas chevron on left sleeve (WWI deployment). Uniform coat dates from 1926-1940, based on belt and lapel type.
  - Three cadet Colonels posing in dress uniforms circa 1932, P002:061; 2.0 3 x 5 photographic prints (Box 1)
    Posed photograph of 3 cadet Colonels, circa 1932. Dress uniforms include high leather boots with ceremonial spurs with riding pants (Jodhpurs) indicating cavalry cadets officers. Sam Browne belts as issued during period. The last year that OSC had cavalry cadets was 1929, this is a more probable dating of photograph.
  - Overnight encampment on campus Weatherford Hall parade field, circa 1936; P002:064; 1.0 4x5 negatives 1 4x5 negative 2 photographic prints 6x10 and 3x5 (Box 1)